GPU Modification
In the Mavis Designer 2024.2 version, we optimized the GPU simulation.
In this version update, the GPU simulation conflict processing has been greatly improved.
This jacket is made up of a large number of panels, and the particle diameter of the panel is 5.
When dragging the panel, there is no layer gap problem, and the simulation is stable and effective.
The GPU simulation in the new version is more stable and smooth when dealing with the conflict between the panel and the panel or the panel and the virtual model.
Now let's take a look at the update of the simulation menu.
First of all, in the simulation type, the animation of the new animation used to record the cloth animation is completed.
In addition, at the bottom of the simulation type,
there is an option to switch between CPU or GPU simulation.
Now when choosing the type of simulation, you can choose to use CPU or GPU to complete the simulation.
The preview of the simulation of the various simulations used to simulate with GPU is empty.
Since the 2024.2 version, we have improved the accuracy of the GPU simulation,
so that the GPU simulation and CPU simulation can have almost the same result.
Now, through the updated GPU simulation, you can get the same excellent simulation results while improving the efficiency of the work.
Next, let's actually compare the GPU simulation with the CPU simulation.
By looking at the data statistics in the bottom left corner of the 3D window, you can see the relevant data and FPS rate of the version.
In the video, these versions have a number of more than 110,000 points.
Let's first choose the default setting of normal speed to simulate.
On the left side is the GPU simulation effect, on the right side is the CPU simulation effect.
This video is not accelerated.
You can see that although there is a huge difference in speed, the final simulation results are almost exactly the same.
Now let's test the conflict processing function of the GPU simulation.
Although it is now a three-layer version, the simulation can still be completed very smoothly.
When recording high-quality animation, the GPU simulation will also save you work time and improve efficiency.
The video shows the real-time recording effect without acceleration.
The video right here is the recent fat Unknown test faze.
Because it is a GPU simulation, the speed of simulation will differ depending on the Syngar washing block you used.
According to blogs in the previous video, GPU simulation has significantly improved speed.
must be miniscule
Please note that GPU simulation can not be applied to foi flogging and rarity model simulation at the moment.
In the previous version, the simulation information will be recorded in the project file, but from this version, the GPU simulation information will not be stored in the costume project file or the simulation attribute setting file.
In the 2024.2 version, the copy key can maintain the conflict effect in the simulation.
Right-click on the copy key and select the new simulation related function in the menu.
The new three functions are freeze, activate and counter-activate.
Now, when the copy key activates, it can be simulated with the board at the same time and conflict with the board at the same time.
When simulating, you can adjust its position by pressing the left mouse button to drag and drop the copy key.
When dragging and dropping the copy key, you can see that the packaging material will also move along with it.
The copy keys of the package or ring type are usually smaller, and the space that the board can pass through is smaller.
Considering this situation, please reduce the size of the board.
Please reduce the size of the board.
The thickness of the copy key will give you a more stable simulation effect.
When simulating, you can modify the weight of the copy key.
You can go to the copy key window, find the copy key type, and then go to the attribute editor to modify it.
When you freeze the copy key, it will be frozen in the 3D window.
It will not be affected by weight or weight.
You may have the ability to change the position of the copy key with the help of the 3D window.
When resizing the copy key, it will not be affected by the 3D window.
When resizing the copy key, it will be free of the simulation of the 3D window.
Now, when you calculate the collision of the adhesives, the adhesives will no longer stick to the point as the standard, but will make the entire surface of the adhesives participate in the collision.
Now you can adjust the hardness of the adhesives.
When an adhesives is activated, you can select it and then go to the attribute editor to modify its hardness.
If the adhesives are relatively soft, please reduce the hardness value, so that it will have some bending and stretching effects with the simulation.
Select the area of ​​the fabric to be dragged.
In order to better simulate clothing and adjust the details of clothing, you can select the drag range when dragging the clothing fabric.
If you want to activate the drag, please open the simulation and select the move tool.
Then right-click on the 3D window and select the drag option.
Or you can press Shift E to activate this function.
After activating the drag function,
you will see the window that will be used to set the attribute.
The settings in this window are divided into two pieces.
In the options above, you can see the settings for the drag range.
Here you can set the soft selection of the reduction type, the range and the degree of reduction.
The display range brush is randomly opened.
When you move the mouse, you will see two circles that indicate the soft selection.
The outer circle indicates the range of soft selection, and the position of the inner circle indicates the degree of reduction.
Now we turn on the full weight display.
When the full weight display is turned on, the part of the soft selection will show green.
The reduction type is divided into two types, the curve and the straight line.
The curve and curve are different in different reduction types.
In addition, the curve is also affected by the degree of reduction.
Now let's set the soft selection range and the degree of reduction to the highest to see the difference between the two reduction types.
When we set it to the straight line, the center range of soft selection is very small.
When we set it to the curve, the center range of soft selection is wider.
When we set it to the curve, the center range of soft selection is larger.
We return all the values to default settings.
There are two methods of measuring the range, surface measurement or straight measurement.
When the measurement method is set to the surface, the soft selection will be applied to the surface of the plate you click with the soft selection brush.
Therefore, your choice will only work on the selected plate.
If the measurement range is set to the line,
the soft selection will be applied to all the 3D spaces.
This measurement method is more suitable for soft selection of multi-layered clothing.
By clicking on the button that only works for selected panels, your soft selection will only work for selected panels.
It is not affected by the range measurement method of selection.
This option is very effective for panels that are glued together after some simulation.
Go-Z plug-in optimization
Next, we will introduce Go-Z plug-in optimization updates in the 2020.2 version.
You can click on the help bar in the main menu to install Go-Z and go to the Go-Z handbook to download the corresponding plug-in.
When the installation is complete, you can see the Go-Z menu in the main menu.
As you can see, the current 3D window of Go-Z is in the main menu.
Please go to the main menu, click on Go-Z, and then click on the ZBrush.
The settings in the ZBrush window are mainly divided into two pieces.
At the bottom of the item menu bar, you can select which objects to export.
For example, all virtual models, panels, accessories, or scenes and props.
Or it is based on the need to select or cancel the selection of a specific object.
The merge or unselect the merge option is used to set whether the sewing line is connected to the top of the clothing box.
At the bottom, you can select whether to bring thickness.
Or whether to bring thickness to the top of the clothing box.
At the bottom of the basic menu bar, you can set the unit and storage ratio of the export.
Click on Confirm to complete the export.
Now you can see the various objects imported in the Subtool menu and have automatically assigned a multi-layer group.
In the import settings window, you can set the loading type, object type, unit and storage ratio.
In the loading type, you can choose to open it and import the file as a new one.
Or choose to add the file to the existing project file.
In the object type, you can choose to import the file as a virtual model, accessory, clothing, or scene and props.
You can choose based on the need.
Finally, you can set the unit and storage ratio based on the need.
Now let's try to import a character from ZBrush to Marvelous Designer.
Go to ZBrush and click Go Z to import the character into Marvelous Designer.
We have already set the object type as Avatar.
The character will be imported into Marvelous Designer in the form of a virtual model.
You can continue to use the virtual model related functions and wear the costume on it.
Now let's try to import the character from ZBrush.
We will import the character from ZBrush in the form of a virtual model.
You can see that the character will be imported into Marvelous Designer.
Use the parameter from the 3D printer to import the character.
The character is also imported into Marvelous Designer to bring the character to Marvelous Designer.
You can add a character and import each character in the form of a virtual model.
Here is the information about the new ZBrush set of available settings.
To install the ZBrush, you can click the button on the top of ZBrush.
Below it, there are three options, you can choose whether to display the front, back, and seam allowances of the board.
In order to make it easier to see, we will change the style of the clothing display to the white surface of the display thickness and frame.
By adjusting the thickness of the rendering, you can increase or decrease the thickness of the side of a board.
There are three settings for the direction of squeeze, front, back, and full.
When choosing the front, the thickness of the side of the board will be squeezed forward based on the front of the board.
When choosing the full, the same as the previous version, the thickness is squeezed to the front and back of the board at the same time.
When choosing the back, the thickness of the side of the board is squeezed backwards based on the back.
At the bottom of the squeeze direction, you can choose whether to display the front, back, and seam allowances of the board.
When you cancel the selection,
the front of the board selected after the front option will no longer be displayed.
Similarly, if you cancel the selection of the back, the back of the board will be hidden.
If you continue to display the grid, you only need to click on the corresponding option again.
When you click on the selection of the seam allowances, the original hidden seam allowances will be displayed.
The number of sections on the side will affect the layout of the side grid.
The higher the value, the more detailed the side grid, the more natural the transition will be.
It is the same for the top and bottom sections.
In addition to the fact that the curve value can be set high and low,
but when the number of sections on the side is low, it will not provide enough curve effect.
Eventually the side will become a cross-section with no curve.
This is the main new features in 2020.2 version.
For more related information, please refer to the corresponding video for investigation.
Functions and optimization
Next, let's understand some function optimization.
Next, let's take a look at some functions to optimize.
Attach the fixed pin to the symmetrical plate.
After creating a fixed pin on the plate in the symmetrical relationship, it can be applied to the symmetrical plate.
First, we need to remove the symmetrical shoulder strap plate and use the fixed pin tool to create the fixed pin.
You can choose to add a fixed pin to the plate in the 2D or 3D window.
On the top of the grid on a line, double-click to create a fixed pin along the entire line.
Then right-click on the created fixed pin and choose to copy it to the symmetrical plate.
Now you can see that the fixed pin has been copied to the symmetrical plate.
This function is very useful when you need a symmetrical fixed clothing grid.
Adjust the joint size.
In the menu of the 3D window virtual model display menu, choose to display virtual model joints.
A virtual model joint menu will appear in the upper right corner of the 3D window.
At the same time, the virtual model joint will be displayed.
The default virtual model joint size is 8.
As the value is reduced, you will see that the joints are getting thinner and thinner.
The minimum can be reduced to 1.
Increasing the value will make the joints thicker and thicker.
The maximum value can be set to 20.
Click on the reset button to reset the joint thickness to the default value.
Hide selected joints.
You can hide them after selecting certain joints.
In the menu of the 3D window display menu, open the display virtual model joints.
Choose one or more joints.
Then right-click on the selected joint and select Hide joints.
The selected joints will all be hidden.
According to the location of the selected joint, there may be related multiple joints hidden.
The selected joints will be displayed in yellow.
Right-click on the virtual model joint or virtual model.
Select to display all joints.
All hidden joints will be displayed again.
The 4-sided side will be upgraded.
The 4-sided side optimization type grid array algorithm has been further optimized in the new version.
First, we will switch the grid type to 4-sided side optimization option for this set of clothing in the previous version.
After switching the grid type in the previous version, strange 4-sided side shapes will appear in some unnecessary places.
Open the high quality rendering to predict the effect of entering other software.
The unreasonable placement of these grid lines will cause some grid points to be squeezed out, resulting in an unideal rough effect.
In the new version, we have a more neat and clean four-sided grid line.
There are no extra four sides before.
As before, you will see that since the grid line is more reasonable, the clothing will no longer be the same as before.
Please check the comparison picture, you can see that now we have a more reasonable grid line on the four sides of the transition.
The lines fit the settings.
Now you can set the two ends of the line to match.
In this example, we will use the grid tool to create a circle grid along the seat.
After selecting the grid, go to the property editor and you will see the new grid menu.
Here you can click on the two ends of the grid to match.
You can see that when the grid is set to the end point, it will match like in real life.
Now we will increase its width and decrease its strength.
You can use the grid tool to adjust the length of the grid.
As the length is changed, the closed area will also be automatically modified into a natural shape.
Through the closed function, you can create a more natural grid effect, making the details of the clothing or furniture more real.
Now you can set the extension settings of the grid.
First, select the 2D grid to adjust the length of the grid.
First, select the extension tool in the 2D tool bar to add a grid along the outside of the board.
In the 2D window, you can see that the newly added grid has various colors.
Now you can set whether the two ends of the grid are extended to other positions.
You can refer to the arrow on the line of the grid. The arrow at the end point is the end point.
You can set different extension settings for the two ends.
In addition, you can choose to extend to the outside of the board, stretch or not.
When the beginning and end of a grid are located at the same point,
open the extension to the stretch bar for both ends at the same time.
This will make the stretch bar on both ends extend to the cross position and will not overlap.
There are three types of extension for stretch bars.
5. To the outside of the board to stretch bar
6. To the outside of the board to stretch bar
You can refer to the stretch bar in the map to see how these extension settings work.
For more information, please go to Marvelous Designer official website to read the relevant manual.
Thank you for watching, see you in the next video.